Louise McCallum.
No one ever really said much about her.
Just that I had a great aunt who died young.
Guessing they never mentioned she had a husband.
No.
But I don't think you can blame them.
You were convicted of her murder.
Yeah.
You were so anxious to see me.
Why'd you wait all these years to write?
Your aunt Nell, she asked me not to.
I don't mean to be rude, Mr. McCallum,
but even if I did believe your story,
I don't know what you want me to do.
I just need someone in Louise's family to know
I truly love my wife.
I'm not the man who killed her.
Louise!
It was 42 years ago,
and I can still hear those shots.
Louise.
Louise!
No!
Sheriff Tate arrived.
Dex!
Louise!
You out here?
He found me with a gun,
and Louise dead in my arms.
Dex.
What have you done?
I swear to you,
that's what happened that night.
When I saw your picture in the paper,
I couldn't get over how much you looked like Louise.
I thought,
if you are anything like her,
you'd be the one person who could understand.
If you're saying,
that you didn't kill her,
then who did?
The man I saw leaving the barn,
the drifter,
he killed my Louise.
Somebody say
that you won't let us break right through.
Somebody save me.
Don't care how you do it.
Just stay, stay.
Come on.
I've been waiting for you.
Just stay.
I made this whole world shine for you.
Come on.
What happened to this guy?
This drifter?
They never caught him.
Dexter said that people assumed that he made the story up so that he could cover his tracks.
But you believe him.
Well, why would he lie to me?
It's not like he's gonna get the last 40 years of his life back.
Lana convicted murderers,
spent half their day trying to convince people they're innocent.
Clark, that drawing looks exactly like you.
So unless Dexter could have predicted the future,
there's a pretty good chance that Drifter was real.
He could have been your grandfather.
Even your father.
That's impossible.
Why? You must have come from somewhere.
It's not like you just fell out of the sky.
I think Lana's right. It is Jewel.
From 1961?
These cave walls said that people from Krypton had been here before.
Why not my father?
Clark.
Seth, don't you think you're trying just a little bit too hard to make a connection.
You saw the medallion he was wearing. The symbol's Kryptonion.
OK, let's just say that it was Jarell.
Now from everything I know about him,
it's not that far of a stretch to believe that he could kill somebody.
That's the thing. We don't know that much about him.
Up until now, all Jarell has been to me is some distant powerful threat.
But if he was here, walking the same streets as me,
maybe we're not so different.
Maybe he's more human than we thought.
Clark.
Clark,
Clark, isn't that what you're looking for?
I knew I'd seen it down here.
Clark. Clark!
What is that?
The images I saw must have been from the past.
Clark.
You really need to lay off the late night television.
I'm not kidding, Pete.
I had all these flashes, but they went by so fast,
I really couldn't make sense of them.
I'm a single one foot to walk over my door
I ain't got no matches, but I got a long way to go
I'm an old boy, boy, long way from home
Guess I'll never be happy, everything I do is wrong
Give it over.
Get away from me.
Give me the money. I know you've got it.
Give it. Come here.
Give it.
My hero.
You don't strike me as someone who usually needs help.
You don't strike me as someone who usually needs saving.
Thank you.
Did you see that?
You could have killed me.
Tell it to the judge.
Thanks.
I'm Louise.
You can call me Joe.
Well, Joe?
You're the most exciting we've had all year.
Watch your head.
Well, I guess we owe you our gratitude.
Okay.
Hi, I'm Sheriff Billy Tate.
Some reflexes you got there.
They kind of surprised me too.
Haven't seen your own Smallville before.
I'm just passing through on my way home.
Lucky you.
Forgive Louise. She's got stars in her eyes.
Always has.
There's nothing wrong with that.
Louise?
Everything all right?
You go on home, Louise.
I know how Dex hates to miss his bridge game.
I'll drop by and get your statement.
I'll see you around.
Listen?
I don't have time for you books.
We need to take that.
I don't believe those homeless.
Very good news.
♥
Team Dex on the left.
WRITTEN MEMORIES
Appreciate your help.
Clark, what's going on?
Looks like I was back in the 50s.
He's standing right here where Joe was.
Joe?
That's the name of the drifter.
Pete, do you remember when I was in the cave
and I got all those flashes?
I think this medallion downloaded me
with all his memories.
When I touch something of his, it triggers one.
Right.
Louise was here too.
The drifter, he saved her.
Of course he did.
Clark, back here in the 21st century,
we call that a daydream.
There's got to be a way to find out
if what I saw really happened.
Since when can you take police records out of City Hall?
Since I caught the clerk and his girlfriend playing
cops and robbers while I'm job.
Well, the robbery should be around June 1961.
That's when the movie was playing at the talent.
OK, I don't mean to give you the third degree,
but how do you know all of them?
Chloe?
I told you it was just a hunch that the drifter was there.
Yeah, I get that.
It's the robbery outside the talent
with the Natalie Wood movie playing
that's a little more detailed than your average hunch.
Well, as curator of the wall of weird,
just go with me on this one.
OK.
There's some pages missing, all from the day
of Louise's murder.
Someone gets a D in subtlety.
All right, well, here's the robbery.
You see our heroic drifter anywhere?
No, but look at the name of the robber.
Lachlan Luther.
That's Lex's grandpa.
Oh, come on.
I had a three megabyte file on Lex.
I know his favorite cereal.
Maybe he knows something.
Well, you're going to have to find out.
I got to meet Lana.
Nell found some of Louise's things in the attic.
Clark, this is where I'm going to have to bail.
The last time I researched the Luthers, Lex almost got killed.
Please.
You're going to have to deal with him sooner or later.
I always thought you were a good cop.
I'm not a good cop.
I'm not a good cop. I'm not a good cop.
I always assumed my father's knack for taking people's money was inherited, but I hardly
think petty crime runs in the family.
Well, Smallville isn't exactly teeming with Lachlan Luther's.
Your grandfather has to be the one who was arrested.
Chloe, no one in my family set foot in this town until my father bought the cream corn
factory.
Isn't an age-old robbery a little off your usual team beat?
No, this one's pro bono.
Lana's really worried about her great uncle.
Something tells me you're not here because of Lana.
Anyway, we think Lachlan met the Drifter and we were just hoping that we...
What?
My family sat around at Thanksgiving, sharing old crime stories?
Your family isn't exactly a Norman Rockwell painting.
Look, Lex, we're just trying to find what we can.
I wish I could help you, Chloe.
But I'm afraid you're a little too young to be a good cop.
Yeah.
I'm afraid you've met a dead end.
Hey.
Hi, Lana.
Look, I'm really sorry about being so defensive this morning.
You don't have to apologize.
I kind of dumped a lot on you all at once.
I'm sorry.
I guess it's just when you're adopted you dream about where you came
from and what your birth parents were like.
Your biggest nightmare is that they were criminals.
With all the strange surprises I've had in my family, I know it's not easy.
There are only a few of Louise's things.
But I think we'll be able to find something.
Oh.
It's a love letter.
Dexter must have written this.
I don't know.
Who knew he could be so, um...
Passionate?
Only an initial?
Could you?
I couldn't stop thinking about you all day.
I've never felt this way about anyone.
All I know is I want to be with you.
I love you.
All right.
I'll be waiting please.
You're not required to write this letter.
Just remember this.
Thank you.
Bye!
All right.
But they all disappear
From view
And I only have eyes
What?
Lana, I don't think that love letter's from her husband.
I think it's from the Drifter.
They were in love.
Congratulations, Lex. That was an excellent presentation.
The board was impressed.
There's smoke and mirrors, but...
it's skillfully done.
What can I say? I guess the art of deception runs in the family.
And the day was off to such a sweet start.
Deception, huh?
You think I've been deceiving you about something?
You tell me.
I've always described Grandfather Lachlan as a hard-working entrepreneur
who came from Scottish nobility.
What are you driving at, son?
Maybe you could explain why Lachlan Luther was arrested
in 1961 for petty robbery in Smallville.
Not all entrepreneurs can have the luxury
of being both successful and honest.
Why would you go to such lengths to hide our past?
When I was young and trying hard to get a foothold
in the world of overachieving Ivy Leaguers,
I quickly found that confessing to the fact
that I was born and bred in a place like Suicide Slum
wasn't gonna win anybody over at a cocktail party.
So you took the liberty of rewriting our family history?
That's right. Why should I have to pay for the sins of my father?
Sounds familiar.
Is the, uh, memorial and our family plot even real,
or do I have grandparents wandering around Suicide Slum?
No, no, they...
They both died...
in a tenement fire.
In a tenement fire.
The only reason I'm alive is I was moonlighting at the...
at a print shop when it happened.
Ever since then, I've, um, buried myself in work...
consciously.
I've been a man of my word.
This is the barn where Louise was shot.
Clark, it's been over 40 years.
What do you expect to find here?
I'm sorry.
No, Louise.
That's a gift.
We're not that different, Joe.
I'm willing to try.
This wasn't supposed to happen.
I have to return home alone.
Why?
Because it's my destiny and I can't change it.
Louise, as much as I want this, I can't have it.
My father told me that someday I'd understand.
That my actions have consequences.
I guess this is what he meant.
It's not fair.
We should be together.
I'm sorry.
Louise.
Oh.
Joe.
No.
Louise.
Don't leave me.
I'll never leave.
I love you.
Louise.
No.
No, Louise.
Louise.
Clark?
I know who killed her.
The Edgecliff Condos.
They're owned by Luther Corp.,
but I'm missing the connection
to my grandpapa.
What happened to your grandparents?
Well, before the condos
and the coffee houses,
this was the worst part
of suicide slums.
That high rise?
It stands on the site of the tenement
your grandparents died in.
So my father's story's true.
They died in a fire.
Yeah, if you call an explosion
that blows the windows
out of two city blocks,
it's a fire. Yeah.
Sounds like you have your doubts.
I was a detective in that precinct.
Back in those days,
when they told you to drop a case,
you did it.
The slumlords controlled City Hall.
Well, I'm retired now.
It doesn't really matter.
I think you'll find my original report
in lightning.
I don't mean to rain on your parade, but...
Lockburn Luther was in the jail
at the time of the murder.
I know it was him.
How?
You can't keep expecting us
to follow these weird hunches
without telling us what's going on.
It's crazy.
You passed crazy
about four random clues ago.
Ever since I read that newspaper article,
I've been having memories from 1961.
What?
It's like some weird deja vu thing.
Could it be like reincarnation?
You know, like past lives?
Chloe.
Or genetic memory.
You know, science has theorized
that we store our ancestors' memories in our DNA.
Anyway.
Wherever your hunches are coming from,
they're eerily accurate.
Look at this.
I asked the ledger to email me
the newspaper's police blotter
from the day that was missing in the logbook.
Lockburn was released from jail
the morning Louise was murdered.
I only spent a few nights in jail
for armed robbery?
Yeah, and look at the name of the deputy
who released him.
Billy Tate.
More affectionately known now
as our honorable Mayor William Tate.
Tex and Louise were my best friends.
Arresting him was the hardest thing
I ever had to do.
You bear a striking resemblance
to your great aunt.
Has anyone ever told you that?
Mayor Tate, do you remember booking
someone named Lachlan Luther?
He was released the same day Louise was killed.
It's hard to keep track
of all the arrests that I've made.
We think your friend Dexter is innocent.
Trust me.
Of all people, I wanted to believe that
more than anyone.
But finally, I had to admit
there was no drifter.
He made up the story to cover his own guilt.
And to
sign up to the police.
You can be sure about this,
he'll call appealing law.
So what I'm doing to you is
paying a overarching debt of goodness
and loving kindness more than anything
I can ever get aICEA.
Well, Bill, that's a good enough
excuse to do the job.
You know you gotta get back here.
Hey.
I'll phone you later.
Well, if it's really this time
that I definitely can get you do it.
So anyway,
if there's nothing else
you want me to do,
can I benefits tieneats
or someone in your unit in the end?
Oh, hey everyone.
Wir Clinic.
I'll take the next枚,
bye.
You better move along before you cause any more trouble.
Billy.
He was just taking me home.
You better make sure this is what you want, Louise.
Because I think you're making a huge mistake.
I never wanted to marry Dexter.
Don't get me wrong, he's a nice man.
He's just safe.
I made the mistake of telling my father my dreams.
I want to go to Hollywood.
Become a star.
Next thing I know, he's putting me together with Dex.
Saying what a great wife I'd make.
I finally gave in.
And here I am.
I think our fathers would get along.
You see, I'm not what you'd call a model son.
My father sent me here as sort of a lesson.
I didn't want to come here.
I would give anything to stay.
I can't.
Then take me with you.
We'll be like James Dean and Natalie Wood in Rebel Without a Cause.
It'll be romantic.
I don't think you understand.
When I said I wasn't from here, I wasn't talking about Smallville.
Where I'm from, we have colors that you've never seen.
Our moons are so close, they fill up half the sky.
We have sunsets that last for hours.
You almost had me there.
For a second, I was actually believing you.
So, long ago.
One funny story.
That I may have to tell you this Danger.
I went to a bar after party with two men.
And lost most out of drugs.
Then, as you know, having保land on me was awful.
At the30th I walked by and realized I lost six weak men.
You feel it?
22 rating 16 will not wear to the body age with the men who make one mark.
Miss Sinister, bestseller at 2008,
Let's start with this story.
Oh, my God.
So you want me to dredge up an investigation
that was put to bed 40 years ago?
The mayor knows more than he's telling.
Oh, yes, that mysterious drifter of yours.
We think that Mayor Tate made a deal
to drop the charges on Lachlan Luther
if Lachlan killed the drifter.
They were gonna pin the whole thing on Dexter.
Well, you make a great storyteller, Mr. Kent,
but not much of a detective.
See, I will need two small things called motive and evidence
before I'm gonna haul the leader of our community off to jail.
Look.
The handwriting on the police log matches this love letter.
It's the same signature.
He was in love with her as well.
With the drifter dead and Dexter in jail for his murder,
Mayor Tate could have Louie's all to himself.
I don't know if you kids could hear yourselves,
but you might want to be careful
about who you're pointing fingers at.
If you'll excuse me, I got a few cases
in this century to attend to.
Martha, we can't even tell if these visions are for real.
For all we know, they could be just another test from Jarrell.
Jonathan, you're right.
I don't know if you've seen Clark this determined for no reason.
I know this is hard, but we can't blame him
for wanting to know about his birth parents.
Every time I hear the name Jarrell,
all I can think of is that we aren't his real birth parents.
We're just the people who were lucky enough to find him, that's all.
But right now, he's here with us.
Yeah.
Clark, have you had any more of the visions?
No.
Listen, son, I'm sorry I doubted you.
If you'd like, we can go to McCallum's barn,
see if you missed anything.
What is it?
That's Grandpa's gun.
I saw it in the cave when I had my first vision.
It's in the back of your bag.
I don't want any trouble.
I'm just cutting through your field.
Easy there, son.
You already got one murder on your hands
if you're the one the whole town's looking for.
I didn't do it.
I'm not a killer.
I loved her.
I'd never hurt her.
You got to trust me.
I'm going to make sure you don't hurt anyone.
You got to trust me, son.
And Hiram.
Hiram Kent.
What is it?
The drifter was here.
He was here on the farm with Grandpa Kent.
I haven't opened this
since the day my father passed away.
Maybe something in here will trigger another memory.
Clark,
your grandfather wore this old thing
every single day
of his life.
It was his favorite belt.
I wish you could have met him.
Do you recognize anything
from your visions?
At least you won't stand out as much if they stop you.
I know all the back roads.
We'll take them.
I appreciate your help,
but I'll find my way on my own.
I'm not staying here alone.
Make sure these friends of yours are going to show up.
They'll be there.
You're welcome to stay.
We can try to clear this thing up.
We've got no reason to stay anymore.
Be careful.
Bye, Jean.
Bye.
His name is Jonathan.
We're still deciding.
Come on, let's go.
Thank you.
Grandpa helped him escape.
Now look, I'd like to believe you, Clark, but...
He wanted to name you Jean.
Jean.
It was after Jean Autry.
I just knew Jean was going to go have the girl that I showed you.
After Jean Autry.
Mm-hmm.
John.
And what about uyh.
First love.
I like that song.
Sheriff Tate.
Mr. Kent.
I'm not sure how you got in here, but I don't find this very amusing.
I think you've got me confused with someone else.
The police are on their way.
Where did you get that?
I knew you'd remember me.
It just can't be real.
You've done a pretty good job of hiding what's real.
I know you made a deal with Lachlan to kill me.
But how did you feel
when you found out
that he killed Louise instead?
It was supposed to be you.
You can't kill me.
I'm already dead.
For God!
If you ever want another day of peace,
you'll confess what you've done to the sheriff.
No!
I'm not going to jail!
You're not taking the easy way out.
Mayor Tate.
You okay?
We got the silent alarm.
He's trying to kill me.
Who?
Lachlan was supposed to kill the drifter.
I never meant to hurt Louise.
I loved her.
I loved that bitch.
She was the only one that I ever liked.
Is Minnesota the only place
that people can ask for fame?
I careful my eyes.
Yup.
Are you okay?
I think I hit her several times.
And that was it.
No, her cell phone...
It wasn't a cell scene.
I was born inside.
It happened.
And him confessing after all these years...
...doesn't make any sense.
Maybe I'd have been haunting him.
It'd be a terrible thing when love consumes you and takes over.
I was so in love with Louise.
I just couldn't see.
She didn't feel the same way about me.
I wish I'd known when to let go.
The explosion originated in your family's apartment.
There were traces of ammonium nitrate, Dad.
Your parents' death was no accident.
I've always suspected this. I...
I knew my father had enemies, but...
That's not what you told the police.
I was young, but never naive.
I knew automatically that whoever did it would be watching me.
So you knew they were murder.
It's not like you to pass up a chance at revenge.
I had no resources. Couldn't pursue it.
Then? What about the last 30 years?
I couldn't bring them back.
There was nothing I could do, so...
I chose to...
move on, forget about it.
But you can.
Can you?
No.
I owe you a thank you, son.
Your grandparents were murdered.
They deserved to die.
They were killed.
They deserved justice.
Oh, I was such a fool.
I always thought that their murder could stay buried in the past.
We both know...
that's not gonna happen until we find out who did this.
Clark?
Lana, how's Dexter?
I think he's just relieved that his name's finally been cleared.
Personally, I think I'd be more relieved
knowing I wasn't getting locked up again.
I'm not quite sure why,
but I think Dexter has you to thank for his freedom.
You're the one who believed in him.
Yeah.
He was wrong about the Drifter.
I'm not so sure he was.
Nothing would have happened to Louise
if she didn't fall in love with him.
I know what Louise did was wrong,
but I can't help thinking she was lucky.
Even if it was only for a few days,
she knew what it felt like to really be in love.
I'm sorry, Dexter.
But what if you were my love?
It's too bad it couldn't last.
Well, what if that's not the point?
Maybe you have to be grateful for the time that you spend together.
Stop holding on to what could have been.
What is it, Clark?
What are we doing here?
I'm not sure.
What are you doing with that thing?
We're supposed to return it to my father.
There's too many bad memories attached.
Thank you, Hiram.
I can usually tell an honest man when I see one.
Sorry you ran into trouble here.
There's plenty of good folks at Small Hill.
I'll remember that.
Congratulations on the baby.
He's lucky to have you as parents.
If there's anything you ever need,
you know where to find me.
We've tried all kinds of ways to help thecję we foundummy,
we put
our lives nu
on the line.
Clark.
What did you see?
He buried this here because he didn't want his father to have it.
It acts as some sort of journal.
I think Jor-El was sent here as some kind of rite of passage.
Grandpa Kent was down here, too.
He told Joe that if there was anything he needed...
What is it, Clark?
I don't think you and Mom found me by accident.
I think you were chosen.
We werevine kids, too.
No matter how foolish a man has students...
The guns left...
and they weaved into the shop candlestick in the patibo
You'd never've even understood me.
The money was back...
I mean with that money I was worry-free.
The audience loved me.
I just thought this was my first gig as an artist.
The more it's worth the better.
I'm so nice to this Penthouse too.
I need to save up meat for the diner.
Alright, please.
Any idea?
Okay!
Ready?
Go go!